[
    {
        "question": "What subtle hint in a conversation about a magical creature suggests a future betrayal in the first book?",
        "answer": "Hagrid's mention of Fluffy's weakness to music foreshadows Quirrell's knowledge.",
        "list of reference": [425,426],
        "id": 511
    },
    {
        "question": "Which object in Dumbledore's office during Harry's first visit hints at a secret kept until the final book?",
        "answer": "The Pensieve.",
        "list of reference": [3809],
        "id": 512
    },
    {
        "question": "What seemingly trivial gift given at Christmas in the first year later aids in a life-saving escape?",
        "answer": "The flute from Hagrid.",
        "list of reference": [443, 627, 635],
        "id": 513
    },
    {
        "question": "Which chess piece's movement in the underground chamber mirrors a character's sacrifice in the final book?",
        "answer": "The knight, reflecting Ron's bravery.",
        "list of reference": [654, 656, 657],
        "id": 514
    },
    {
        "question": "What cryptic phrase used by Dumbledore in Book 5 foreshadows the nature of Horcruxes revealed in Book 6?",
        "answer": "'In essence divided.'",
        "list of reference": [5235],
        "id": 515
    },
    {
        "question": "Which creature's behavior in the forest contradicts its usual nature, hinting at a hidden protector?",
        "answer": "The centaurs, influenced by Firenze's actions.",
        "list of reference": [590, 593],
        "id": 516
    },
    {
        "question": "What minor detail about the Mirror of Erised makes its meaning a puzzle to solve??",
        "answer": "Its inscription is written backwards.",
        "list of reference": [464],
        "id": 517
    },
    {
        "question": "What overlooked comment about a pet in the second book foreshadows a character's true identity?",
        "answer": "Scabbers' unusually long lifespan hints at Peter Pettigrew.",
        "list of reference": [2306],
        "id": 518
    },
    {
        "question": "What substance, introduced through an ancient creatureâ€™s attack, is later revealed to bypass magical self-repair and destroy a Horcrux?",
        "answer": "Basilisk venom.",
        "list of reference": [1431, 7797],
        "id": 519
    },
    {
        "question": "What specific phrase in a prophecy-like warning hints at a traitor's identity?",
        "answer": "The servant returns' points to Pettigrew.",
        "list of reference": [2473],
        "id": 520
    }
]